// Creating an array and passing the question number, options and answer

let questions = [
    {
        question: "How many Carbons in a Hexose sugar?",
        answer: "6",
        options: [
            "5",
            "6",
            "7",
            "8"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the bonds that join Oxygen to the Hydrogen elements in a water molecule?",
        answer: "Covalent",
        options: [
            "Strong Bonds",
            "Hydrogen",
            "Ionic",
            "Covalent"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: " which part of the water molecule has a slightly negative charge?",
        answer: "Oxygen",
        options: [
            "Hydrogen Bonds",
            "Oxygen",
            "Covalent Bonds",
            "Hydrogen"
        ]
    },

    {
        question: "Why does water have surface tension?",
        answer: "Hydrogen Bonds",
        options: [
            "Bond Angle",
            "Hydrogen Bonds",
            "Ionic Bonds",
            "Covalent Bonds "
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these properties of water makes it a good environment for living organisms?",
        answer: "All the options",
        options: [
            "High Latent Heat of Fusion",
            "Universal Solvent",
            "High Specific Heat Capacity",
            "All the options"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the general formula for a carbohydrate?",
        answer: "(CH2O)n",
        options: [
            "C6H12O6",
            "(CH3)O6",
            "n=Cn(H30)n ",
            "(CH2O)n"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What are the 3 roles of Carbohydrates in organisms?",
        answer: "Storage, Energy Source, Structure",
        options: [
            "Storage, Energy Source and Transport",
            "Storage, Energy Source, Structure",
            "Energy Source only ",
            "Energy Source and Structure"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "How many Carbon elements are there in a Triposephosphate?",
        answer: "3",
        options: [
            "3",
            "5 ",
            "4 ",
            "6"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "Which structure contain Triosephosphate?",
        answer: "ATP",
        options: [
            "Ribose",
            "ATP",
            "Amylase",
            "rNADH"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "How many carbons are there in a Pentoses Carbohydrate?",
        answer: "5",
        options: [
            "4",
            "5",
            "6",
            "7"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "In which biological structure would you find a pentose carbohydrate?",
        answer: "RNA",
        options: [
            "Glycerol",
            "ATP",
            "RNA",
            "Glucose"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the structural difference between Ribose and Deoxyribose?",
        answer: "No O on carbon 2",
        options: [
            "No OH on carbon 3",
            "No H on carbon 3",
            "No OH on carbon 1",
            "No O on carbon 2"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the difference between Alpha and Beta Glucose?",
        answer: "Alpha has H on top of C1",
        options: [
            "Alpha has H on top of C1",
            "Alpha has OH on top of C1",
            "Alpha has H on top",
            "Alpha has OH on top"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What reagent is used to test for a reducing sugar?",
        answer: "Benedicts",
        options: [
            "Iodine",
            "Biuret",
            "Benedicts",
            "Methylene Blue"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What steps should you follow to test for a non-reducing sugar?",
        answer: "Boil in HCL and neutralise in KOH",
        options: [
            "Boil in HCL and neutralise in H2SO4",
            "Boil in KOH and neutralise in HCL",
            "Boil in Ethanol and add water",
            "Boil in HCL and neutralise in KOH"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the bond between two Alpha Glucose Molecules?",
        answer: "1-4 Glycosidic",
        options: [
            "1-4 Glycosidic",
            "Ester",
            "Peptide",
            "Hydrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What isomer of Glucose is used to form Starch?",
        answer: "Alpha Glucose",
        options: [
            "Alpha Glucose",
            "Beta Glucose",
            "Triosephosphate",
            "Ribose"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the bond that connects Fatty acids to Glycerol?",
        answer: "Ester",
        options: [
            "1-4 Glycosidic",
            "Ester",
            "Peptide",
            "Hydrogen"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What molecule is added to glycerol to produce a Phospholipid?",
        answer: "Phosphate",
        options: [
            "Lipid",
            "Fatty Acid",
            "Carbohydrate",
            "Phosphate"
        ]
    },
    {
        question: "What does the term 'Hydrophilic' mean?",
        answer: "Likes Water",
        options: [
            "Likes Water",
            "Dissolves in Lipid",
            "Dislikes Water",
            "Surface Tension"
        ]
    },

];